MEGHA BHATNAGAR

megha.bhatnagar04@gmail.com 469-951-8212 linkedin.com/in/meghabhatnagar 2385 Diamond Hill Rd, RI,02895

SUMMARY

Enhanced customer experience through Personalization, Measurement & Reporting Strategy for multiple products and programs from concept and design, implementation, measurement, and monitoring. Partnered with engineers to deliver data pipelines and dashboards packaging actionable insights from customer behavior and growth opportunities to leadership using KPIs

TECHNICAL SKILLS

BI Tools: Tableau, PowerBI,QlikView, SAP Business Objects, Microsoft BI(SSIS, SSRS, SSAS), Salesforce, SAS

Programming: T-SQL, PL/SQL, Python, Hive, Scala, Snowflake SQL

DBMS: Azure Data Lake, SQL Server, Oracle 10g, SAP HANA, MY SQL, Hadoop

Other Skills: AB testing, statistical data analysis, UX Design

EDUCATION May 2015- May 2017

MS Information Technology Management, University of Texas at Dallas

TABLEAU PUBLIC - https://public.tableau.com/profile/megha.bhatnagar#!/

EXPERIENCE

CVS HEALTH, MANAGER Nov 2017-Present

Managed product strategy and roadmaps for enhanching customer experience by analyzing customer needs and product data

- Led data strategy, data collection and analysis for evaluating new opportunities and uncovering insights that helped leadership in better defining their marketing strategies.
- Designed the 360 degree patient centric view that enabled better customer alignment, drove customer engagement and loyalty and laid the foundation for predictive analytics using customer behavior.
- Developed executive level weekly business analysis, marketing intelligence and competitor analysis reports unearthing powerful insights contributing to improvement of market penetration by 12% and consumer reach resulting in additional 10M scripts
- Established product and program KPIs to track performance and provide stop or continue recommendations based on data in order to measure the end-to-end customer experience
- Identified product needs by analyzing Member penetration, Disease pattern and Demographics to identify market size proposed business plans and projects.
- Collaborated with cross functional teams to identify gaps and clear business requirements and framed them as analytics problems, developed and scalaled processes to generate insights and presented business recommendations in order to drive changes, to solve the identified issues

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT DALLAS, DATA ANALYST CONSULTANT

Jun 2016- Aug 2016

- Researched and analyzed business processes and procedures and designed and implemented automated business solutions for payroll systems.
- Analyzed and identified process gaps and led the change for process optimization by designing process mapping of current and future business processes
- Created presentations in concise & well-researched manner on new product feature ideas & opportunities by collaborating with product owners.

INFOSYS TECHNOLOGIES, BUSINESS DATA ANALYST

Aug 2011- Jun 2015

- Modelled complex dimension models that helped speed up reporting and analytics for pharmacy database
- Migrated large volumes of data for pharmacy and network security data from multiple sources to target. Leveraged existing
 transformations such as multicast, conditional split, Derived column, data conversion, Lookup, OLEDB command, script
 component, Slowly changing dimension (SCD), merge, join, pivot aggregate etc

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT MANAGER - AGILE LEAD

• Led the ideation and Android/iOS mobile application development the official university mobile app which will be utilized by 90% of active mobile users at UT-Dallas